# Nina Fuentes

Engineer - Technical Specialist

#### Contact

**Address** 

8326 Buckingham Drive Columbus, IN, 47201

**Phone** 

(812) 565-3053

E-mail

nina.fuentes.n@gmail.com

#### **Skills**

**Process Improvement** 

Excellent

Project Management

Excellent

Teamwork / Collaboration

Excellent

6 Sigma Green Belt

Excellent

Leadership

Very Good

Root cause analysis

Very Good

Technical Support

Very Good

Experienced Engineer with international background providing enhanced communication abilities and adaptability. Good time management and effectiveness under pressure are essential qualities that are used on a daily basis. Fast learner and multifaceted employee with both soft and technical skills utilized in current and previous work experience.

#### **Work History**

2018-04 -2019-05

# Product Validation Engineer - Technical Specialist

Cummins Inc., Columbus, IN

- Worked with internal and external stakeholders and team members on quality assurance efforts for water pump and cooling system for L9 Engine
- Demonstrated new product features and functionality to managers and team members
- Collaborated with suppliers and project managers to assess product capabilities, features and testing demands
- Produced and maintained consistent technical documentation

2017-03 -2018-03

## **Senior Field Test Engineer**

Cummins Inc. EDP 4/4, Columbus, Indiana

- Completed 3 hands-on engine builds on various field test units on Stage V 4-cylinder platform
- Managed fleet of over 20 field test vehicles for Viking Platform, communicating with internal and external stakeholders to troubleshoot errors and ensure vehicles ran as scheduled
- Led multiple improvement projects to optimize processes followed by Viking field test team

2016-10 -2017-03

## **Shows and Events Planning Specialist**

Cummins Inc. EDP 3/4, Columbus, Indiana

- Managed planning and execution of Cummins (2) booths for World Ag Expo (Tulare, CA) and UMA Motorcoach Expo (St.-Louis, MO)
- Revamped Show Planning Checklist to improve planning process efficiency



Creole

Spanish

2015-10 - HIT Software Engineer

Cummins Inc. EDP 2/4, Columbus, Indiana

- Resolved 50+ open help tickets for Machine Integration Lab
- Implemented various engine platforms into engine simulation Software (HIT) in LabVIEW
- Programmed fuel rail pressure simulator for IMV-equipped engines
- Integrated GT- Power Models into LabVIEW code to improved Air Handling System simulation

2014-10 -2015-10

### **Product Validation Engineer**

Cummins Inc. EDP 1/4, Seymour, IN

- Engineering Development Program, Rotation 1/4
- Led design reviews (concept reviews, D-phase and P-phase)
- Closed (1) 6 Sigma project on defining architecture of air cleaner enclosure for 78L natural gas engine
- Created and maintained technical profiles, failure analysis, and quality assurance plans for assigned components/systems
- Investigated and resolved failure incidents to ensure fault-free product to customer

#### **Education**

2010-08 -2014-05

**Native** 

Intermediate

# Bachelor of Science: Mechanical Engineering (Math Minor)

Andrews University - Berrien Springs, MI

• Graduated Magna cum Laude (3.86 GPA)

# **Leadership and Professional Development**

Cummins Engineering Development Program (EDP), Graduate / 2014-2018

Cummins Millenials Affinity Group, Vice-President / 2017-2019

EDP Newsletter, Principle Editor / 2017-2018